

# CHIME JULIET SOMTOCHUKWU

FrontEnd Developer(React)

## CONTACT

- +2348135357439
- annychime@gmail.com
- linkedin.com/in/chime-julietsomtochukwu
- https://github.com/Julietchime

## **SKILLS**

- HTML
- CSS
- Bootstrap
- Ant Design
- Material UI
- Javascript
- JQuery
- Typescript
- ReactJS, Redux, Reack Hooks
- Semantic UI
- NPM
- SCSS
- Netlify
- Heroku
- Firebase
- Web development on server side frameworks like WordPress.
- Use of the Git version control system.
- Azure Devops

## **EDUCATION**

RENAISSANCE UNIVERSITY B.SC MICROBIOLOGY

#### **PROJECT**

The Hackathon challenges is task with solving a community problem. I was in a team of four and we came up with an idea to solve an environmental issue which is waste management. We developed a website called 'recyclr' where individuals are expected to scan a code after dropping waste at appropriate site. I was involved with social media and website content creation.

## **PROFILE**

I am a design thinking Frontend Developer with over 3 years experience, passionate about all aspect of technology specializing in core frontend technologies planning, coding, testing and maintaining web applications. while constantly challenging myself and learning new skills in IT and frontend development.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### FRONTEND DEVELOPER

Klasha /Dec 2021 -Till Date

- Working on optimizing cross border payment for e-commerce in Africa
- I built component for sections of the frontend application including the dashboard for monitoring merchant transaction.
- I developed reuseable ReactJs component to make the frontend dvelopment process more efficient and faster.
- I balanced UX and deadline in order to get most of the business values in a limited timeframe.

### FRONTEND DEVELOPER

GIG Mobility /March 2021 -December 2021

- Collaborated with team to build new version of a large scale transport booking platform with improved user experience using ReactJs.
- Collaborated with team to build, implement and maintain internal applications that aggregate all mobility services, so that support personnel can easily monitor all applications, resolve conflicts and ultimately make informed business decisions to grow revenue.
- I developed web applications to optimize the process of users booking experience for transpportation..

## FRONTEND DEVELOPER

SIDEHUSTLE /Aug 2020-Aug 2021

- I balanced UX and deadline in order to get most of the business values in a limited timeframe.
- Created the various interface in javascript ,CSS, HTML,to increase user experience.
- I balanced UX and deadline in order to get most of the business values in a limited timeframe.

#### WEB DESIGNER/ DIGITAL MARKETING ASSOCIATE

Surfweb Digital Solutions /Nov 2019 - March 2021.

- Developed website framework and structure for client website.
- To increase the rating of a client's website, I developed onpage, off-page, and technical SEO techniques.
- I balanced UX and deadline in order to get most of the business values in a limited timeframe.